[Music]
there are nearly a million salmonella
and campylobacter infections in children
10 and younger each year in the united
states some of these infections are
severe causing meningitis and death and
requiring treatment with antibiotics the
problem is that there's an increasing
problem of antibiotic resistance among
these bugs that threatens our ability to
treat them
part of the problem is that these same
life-saving miracle-drug antibiotics are
being squandered for use in food animals
for things like growth promotion in such
unhygienic crowded conditions which
increases the likelihood that pathogens
like salmonella or campylobacter will
become resistant and i've done a bunch
of videos on that but there's another
problem
the resistance determinants the genes
that encode antibiotic resistance
may be transmitted from food animals to
humans through the food supply see most
resistant bacteria have mobile genetic
elements like these little circles of
dna called plasmids that carry the
resistance genes that they can then pass
on to other bacteria including those in
our own gut
food animals are therefore a reservoir
antibiotic resistance genes and a
potential vector for transmission of
antibiotic resistant genes to the human
intestinal microbiome
in this study transfer of an antibiotic
resistant plasmid from an e coli
originating from a chicken race for meat
to human gut bugs was assessed by using
a model that mimics the human intestines
and it happened
within
two hours
this spread of antibiotic resistance
genes presents an alarming scenario a
growing concern that antibiotic
resistant bacteria present on food can
transfer their resistance genes to the
inherent gut microbiome of the consumer
but you don't know
until you put it to the test assessing
antibiotic-resistant gene loads in vegan
versus vegetarian versus omnivore gut
bacteria
you'd think the results might be obvious
but antibiotic resistance genes are
spread due to manure application on
agricultural fields of fruits and
vegetables yes massive antibiotic use in
animal farming is considered as the
greatest contributor to the presence of
antibiotic resistant bacteria and food
of animal origin meats eggs and dairy
nevertheless sewage from treated animals
may impact on vegetables grown on
fertilized fields
but it was largely unknown weather and
to what extent antibiotic resistant
bacteria are being transferred to
vegetables and then to the human gut
until
now
researchers looked for antibiotic
resistance genes against sulfa drugs
like bactrim tetracyclines penicillins
encephalosporins and streptomycin type
antibiotics and
both omnivores and vegetarians showed a
significantly higher
antibiotic-resistant gene load in their
guts as compared with vegans there
wasn't a significant difference between
omnivores and vegetarians but
significantly lower loads in vegans
compared to omnivores and vegans
compared to vegetarians the first
evidence that a vegan lifestyle is
associated with a reduced load of human
gut antibiotic resistant genes but not
the last
fewer tetracycline resistance genes in
vegan guts and more vancomycin
resistance genes than the guts of those
who eat meat
no surprise since they found a
correlation between tetracycline
resistance genes and the intake of eggs
milk and cheese
i like how there are so many types of
milk these days they have to specify
milk from animal source
and a higher incidence of vancomycin
resistance genes was found in consumers
of eggs poultry fish and seafood and
vancomycin is one of our antibiotics of
last resort used to treat serious
life-threatening strep-and-staph
infections like mrsa mrsa
despite the links to dairy and eggs just
cutting out meat has indeed been shown
to offer an advantage in some studies as
bacteria obtained from meat-eater poop
samples showed resistance to a greater
number of antibiotics and carried more
tested antibiotic resistance genes
compared to the vegan or vegetarian poop
[Music]
you